Gothic was one of the first, immersive open world RPGs.
Our job was really to find out, what element should stay
exactly as they are, what element should be expanded.
Throughout the whole production we found ourselves in struggle between old and new.
Making of Gothic remake
Chapter II. Old vs. new
Our approach for the story was like, hey
the original story is actually good, but
it has plot holes,
it has things that are unlogical
and it has things that are contradicting each other.
So our initial think was like,
“Okay we have to set out and fix these three points.”
That was one of my first tasks,
get everything that we can extract from the old games over to like Unreal,
or other tools for our designers to take a look at.
So they can understand how the game worked,
like go through all the conversations,
like a tree size structure um with all the requirements, all the dependencies
between topics, conditions and so on.
Together with the writing team we came up with with solutions
and sometimes we had heated discussions about this because
it's getting very emotional.
We we didn't choose the easiest and most straightforward solution,
but we chose a solution that fits very well in the context of the game.
Now we have Alkimia Narrative tool, as it's called.
The tool that can handle the complexity of the original game's dialogues. The tool that can display that, handle that and you can work with it.
And this was the base for our designers to iterate on the original dialogues,
daily routines AI states, the combat AI is implemented in there.
All the character configuration, what interactions they can do,
what animations they should play.
It’s all in this scripting language and you can go there and modify it as you like.
We even had at one point, a sort of running
version of the original game in Unreal.
The biggest challenge from a design perspective is
the making the world feel alive and hold this work with all the systems
because in the end, we are creating a living world with a lot of characters,
but we are not just configuring the daily routines or their
homes or the the kind of things.
This is a systemic game, so they react to the player actions,
to the all the system, like they are witness of your crimes,
how you enter trespassing a forbidden area,
how you launch an object and they interact with that.
Modernizing these systems with all these the world building
and world setting and make everything works together
is a really, really challenging thing for us.
From a technical point of view, if you have an open world and you can go everywhere,
you need to consider that the world needs to live on while the player is not there.
We actually have for the full world the daily routines,
the living world simulation is always going.
and when you come close to an to an NPC so they spawn,
they will be spawned where they would be if you were just standing there waiting.
For example we have this, we have the templars
walking from the Sect camp to the Old mine
and in the original game you could never meet them in between the camps.
Now you can stand somewhere wait for the full day,
yeah they will arrive at some point.
Then there was the part where we kind of like set out,
well, the German version is iconic
and so is probably the Polish version and the Russian version,
but like the English version is actually not iconic.
Throughout this series it kind of changed style, so that's one thing.
It didn't manage to translate this rough language to the entire like story.
So we set out to do a rework of the English texts
and that was our starting point and why that we discovered even more of these plot holes
and things that we need to improve and make better.
Then there are aspects where we added things, that were just
not touched on enough or in later chapters there's too much shortcuts
about it or there are places in the world that are not used.
The most interesting part of the Gothic Remake would be
the cut content from the original game.
The places that were pretty empty in the original game
and in Gothic Remake we create them
and put here and there new things that would enhance the experience.
We try to make a little bit more interesting the dungeons
and also the way the player can get into the castle.
It’s like very hidden and you can guess that there is
something different there, if you go to the to the Gomez cellar.
One aspect about the story that I can tease here, that we kind of added
and this is like the way how you interact with the Orc culture.
Which I feel like was in the original very base level, I mean you had this interaction
with Ur-Shak and Tarrok.
It was to a level where it was like “Yeah, okay it served a single purpose”
and then it's like you just kill them off.
But I mean the whole thing in the whole Gothic lore,
the whole theme with the orcs is actually the reason why everything is happening.
It's the reason for why the colony exists.
It's the reason for why the barrier exists because without the ore mining,
which is needed for the war you would not have the need to create a barrier.
We felt like we need to give this more space.
As I'm mostly engaged with all the content related to economy,
what I try to do is mine the whole game.
I have a model of the the original game.
Then I try to see patterns.
Patterns that talks to me about how, what was the original intent,
with how the economy evolved, how the progression evolved.
And then I tried to see where those patterns break
because for example in the original Gothic the economical progression,
was quite broken for the last chapters.
You cannot generate value from nothing.
The player should not be the central bank of the economy.
And that also connects with the trading systems because
the traders in the original game were quite passive.
They only regenerated their inventory and the ore between chapters.
But we have a passive system that do some garbage collecting,
so some items are expansed from the economy.
Those items are managed as if they were being traded between the traders,
So those items are converted into ore so there's always liquidity in the market.
There's not an overabundance of materials, so we always have control
of how much you can craft.
At some point the economy will break, I mean it's a closed economy.
It's it's bound to break because the only active agent is the is the character.
But if we can delay that to the sixth chapter that would be the best case scenario.
The the exploration is a key part of the game.
This is a hard technical thing that we've been looking into,
through the whole development, such as giving the players this feeling
of being lost. Once it gets dark you're just lost.
I mean we have a lot of places that even if it's day,
you just get lost, so at night everything is super dark,
but you still can manage your way through.
You can have a lot of spells or even
your own torch that would help you go
through all these places, but definitely if you don't have a good sense of orientation
you gonna get lost.
Each one has its own environment and personality
because all the characters
in each camp are unique in one way or another.
But in the end, when you keep on walking around the world you can see
that all the camps are somehow connected,
characters move from one place to another
and the stories are interrelated among them.
The main idea we have regarding hoarding is to force the player to consume items.
Be it because the combat is difficult, be it because there is some dynamics
that require the use of those items evidently.
There is a problem with all open world RPGs, that it tends to be an
overabundance of items because you don't know where the player is going to be,
where the player is going to look at and you must guarantee a minimum viable
amount of utility for the player to overcome the challenges.
So if you have a very serious player that loots everything and it's a hoarder by nature,
we won't be able to combat that, but at least uh the design
will try to put the player in situations that force them to use the items they have.
With RPGs you tend to spend a lot of time.
In a lot of games you actually get tired of the music at some point,
but in Gothic you never get tired, which is also related to the system that they used back in the day.
There wasn't kind of like a master track, that they would just play back.
It would kind of like layers that depending on what happens in the game world,
it would play different cues, so it kind of like always felt different.
So my main priority when making music is - I want to be
a messenger of emotions.
I want to understand, as the composer I want to understand
the emotional message that is in every single scene in the game.
And I want to be able to kind of push the emotional impact on the player.
It adds a certain depth to the game because you can actually feel what's going on and it
doesn't just work as like background music, but also as its own aspect to the
emotional landscapes.
You can imagine it as painting pictures.
So I imagine a situation for example,
where there's a sense of determination and adventure.
Then I try to come up with an image that represents that.
Sometimes I do abstract drawings, sometimes I pick something from from the internet
and then I look at all those individual visual elements
and try to come up with music ideas for those.
So for example if I have a strong, key image
in the center of my abstract painting for example,
I try to get an idea of what instrument could represent that specific part of the picture.
And then I just play around with it,
I experiment with different melodic ideas, with different harmonies and through
lots of iteration and tinkering around in my software I come to the final result.
I'm most excited actually to get the new or the extended abilities
in the hands of the players, So we've spent a lot of time
analyzing like, what sort of abilities actually don't fulfill the true vision
of what it could make sense in the world of Gothic.
We’ve teased some of it a little bit in the gameplay reveal
with the climbing, will add another dimension and it's similar
actually to the climbing in Zelda, but it's obviously kind of like
limited to certain areas of the game.
And then another thing like we’ve teased, like
first of all we try to kind of like make some interesting underwater path and locations.
So there's a lot to explore there, but also diving is a proper like skill that you need to learn
and get better on.
You can also like interact with objects underwater, which is pretty cool,
so you can pick up loot, you can interact with stuff.
So that's that's all stuff that I feel like, I'm proud that we did it,
like that we don't just copy the original.
Most of the materials will be used for different crafting stations,
so alchemy, cooking, whatever.
The idea is that those recipes will evolve with the player,
so if the player invests points in that those recipes will become useful.
Across the gameplay and also there is an important thing that even
if you don't have immediate utility for that
recipe at that moment, the act of crafting has an inherent value in
reducing the abundance of materials in your inventory
and gaining a bit of ore from the process.
So you spend time in and you gain a lot of utility in ore.
And there's things I'm sure there are things that are controversial,
that people are like "Well you’re contradicting what the original set out".
We tried to limit these things and we wanted to be extra sure that like,
our solution is actually better.
We cannot please everybody.
We hope that players look at it give it a try to understand our motivation
And I'm happy to talk through about this after the game is out
and give detailed reason for why we did the way we did.
Obviously I don't want to spoil things.
Our approach of coping with this struggle between old and new was
being practical and finding a certain baseline, that is always within the
Gothic vision and especially close to the original.
We can't wait to hear what you think about this.
I mean for us we are not done with it.
I mean, like getting started.
(Spanish.) Good morning, Gothic fans!
It's not (yet) time to go hunt some boar
Kai when finalizing the sound for this video "Just a little second more!"
We are just here to crawl in "Gomez" ass
After this video I need to buy another SSD, again!
Gomez knows nothing... yet
May the sleeper awaken!
Wishlist now!