Може містити контент, не рекомендований дітям. Додаткова інформація про вікові рейтинги на esrb.org
Оригінальна Ґотика
була настільки популярною та унікальною в той час, що я відчуваю, що
вона заслуговує на належний римейк.
Створення ремейку Gothic 1
00:00:40:00 - 00:00:43:00
Розділ I - Ґотичний дух
Наш підхід полягав передусім у тому, щоб
поважати та сприймати оригінальне бачення гри.
Ми вивчали оригінальне бачення, намагалися зрозуміти все,
що намагалися сказати, та намагалися донести.
І ми просто подумали: «добре, це ж Ремейк».
Це перше, що повинні розуміти фанати,
ми не намагаємося винайти велосипед або зробити щось божевільне
з франшизи Ґотики.
Це римейк - ми приймаємо,
шануємо оригінальне бачення, і просто намагаємося підходити до цього
з великою повагою.
Через стільки років, а насправді через досить короткий проміжок часу,
після виходу Ґотики 1, коли я повертаюся до музики
що я писав тоді,
Завжди знаходжу речі, які хотілося б покращити.
Якби було більше часу, я б викинув деякі речі
та замінив їх іншими задумами,
це постійно, знаєте,
прагнути та намагатися зробити все якнайкраще.
Тепер з'явився другий шанс, і я можу повернутися до своєї музики
яку я написав тоді, і створювати нові версії,
створювати свіжі версії, які витримують випробування часом.
Минуло понад 20 років з моменту виходу першої ґотики,
і складно думати про те, як
переносити щось, що має таку історію,
до сучасності, з тією якістю життя, яку ми маємо зараз
та як залишатися вірними оригіналу
досвід гри у такій грі,
що була досить інноваційною, зовсім новою
для всього ринку і те, що внесла в рольові ігри.
Я занурився у світ Ґотики
завдяки Каю Розенкранцу та його творам.
And I want to say a big thank you to Snowball localization team,
because they made a huge job.
The voices and localization, it helped me a lot to go deeper in this world.
I think that Gothic 1 was a game that allows
the player to go everywhere, anywhere and anytime.
So that feeling that the player has,
to make his own choices.
There was I don't know, 15 years?
Over 10 years. There was nothing happening with it.
Which is sad because it's like, it's a franchise and the game
the people deeply care about and are very emotional towards to,
and I'm I myself sad actually
that I never got to play another Gothic game in this time.
We are - fighting with memories.
We’re just trying to embrace the original vision of the authors.
When I was young, I've played the games in German.
It was one of the only games
which had a real character and authenticity
to German like culture.
The dialogues were written in a way how
you and me would speak, if we would be, I don’t know, frankly drinking a beer and talking about stuff. Right?
And that is something that, was never done by a game,
like it was so natural and so close to reality
in a way, like without being a simulation or whatever.
Kind of fascinated me always. Right?
because it also like, they were cursing each other in the game
and reacting to each other in a very rude way sometimes,
and that was kind of attractive for me.
I think this game has something special from the start,
right from the moment you begin playing, it grabs you,
it draws you in with that,
with that dark
and tough aura that is established very quickly.
That feeling of being part of the world
is already there in the music, the environments, in everything.
I really liked Gothic, because of the setting and the world.
What really caught my attention was that it was a game
I wasn’t used to playing at the time.
A game that doesn’t guide you, doesn’t tell you where to go
or what to do.
You have to pay attention to what the characters say,
buy the map, and stay very alert.
That’s truly
a very immersive experience,
and I think that’s what I liked most about the game.
Gothic is very grounded game, that you feel like is tough,
it's hard, but it’s also very realistic.
What was amazing to me the first time that I played Gothic was
how you could solve a lot of situations, taking advantage of everyone.
Everyone would take advantage of you of course, but then you have
these chances where you can take advantage of a
character killing a scavenger for you so you can go around something.
I think what I like the most
about Gothic is that it combines magic and everything.
Even though it’s a fantasy game, it’s very believable.
It’s not 100% realistic, but we do try to make it look realistic.
It combines these two worlds
and it doesn’t give you the feeling that you’re
in a game that couldn’t exist in real life,
but rather something that makes you
feel like you’re inside the character and that you could be living that.
The living world - like the simulation that like,
everything has a daily routine, you can affect it.
You can get to discover, kind of like be part of the life.
It was the first simulation that I feel like was not centered
around the player.
It was actually going on while, you know,
you were not a center of attention for everything.
You were just a nobody.
I really like was the progression system
and how you learn abilities and what also the progression
have an impact on
your fighting styles your main character had.
Really, I think everybody struggle fighting against the first scavanger
or run away from the diggers.
And for me this point from then,
learning that all the decisions make sense
and all that affect and in the end of the game
you are stronger and you get "a name" in the colony
for me, that's the most memorable thing of the of the game.
For me them the main thing that for me defines Gothic,
it's the way you interact with other characters.
I mean, it's not about, you know, killing 20 wolves,
and so you get rise in your level of expertise in sword fighting.
It's about find someone, convince him to teach you, how to improve your skills and then
maybe if you are good enough, he will teach you something.
This human relations.
Our aim was also, to create this Remake, in a mindfull way
and with respecting greatly the original,
but we also wanted to setup with the graphics, to be like
a modern game with the realistic look. Right?
And that kinda fights with the original, because the original,
they only had so much polygons for figures for example,
and with these restrictions, you design creatures and NPCs and whatever.
You design it in a very specific way to get the fantasy in your head.
You had to do this, but back in the day.
If there is people who are like,
"Yeah, but I like this look!"
If you really like the look of the original game,
I mean, I think that there is the game for you, which is the original.
And thankfully, I mean, you can now play Gothic 1 and 2 as classic editions
on modern consoles.
Which I think was also
one of our strategies is always to
to take care about franchises and IP’s to make sure,
that thing that people love is actually preserved.
In the end we're fighting to recreate beloved memories,
And in Spanish we say, there is a say:
“Cualquier tiempo pasado fue mejor”
it seems “Any time, any past time was way better”
So in the end, we're trying to challenge
with these, but it's a nice challenge.
So when I see, when I read some fans comments about
and they see for example New Camp, image we released
not much time ago and they say,
“Wow, this is exactly how the New Camp was in my mind, when I was playing.
And then some other fans show him the real image of the New Camp of the original game and they say
“What the hell? What is this?”
In my head it was like the remake one.
So first of all, I think that the fan base of the original
is a multilayered,
demographic and structure.
I think that not one voice that you can listen to and say
if you do it like that, everybody will like it.
And that's, that's the core problem.
There's so many different opinions.
There is even like, when we did the the Gothic Playable Teaser,
there were even like old fans who were like,
“Great finally they are doing something different with it!”
I disagree with this.
I feel like with the the Playable Teaser the aim was to really push
the boundaries and go over it to get strong reactions, and we got that.
So so that worked out.
So back in the day we were asking what fans want, what do they want?
They want to, I mean, the same story with new graphics?
Or maybe a retold? Maybe the one with new story within the world?
Or maybe they want something
in the line of new modern games where the character is always talking
you know, doing jokes to the player, I don't know.
So we thought, okay, let's go stream.
Let's force a very strong reaction.
And with that we can understand what they really want.
And in the end we got the reaction.
We got a lot of ideas from the fans, the fans showed us the way
and they help us to create the the
pillars, the pillars of a Gothic Remake.
I remember four years ago creating a document with the pillars
of the game review and saying, okay, those are the we can not move.
Those are the pillars of everything what we are we constructing
the next years.
Those are the funding pillars and it should be there.
So for me the PT was good because, it helped
us to define those basic pillars.
And we are here today.
When we started to create the real Gothic 1 Remake and got the green light to do it,
we set out to, or we defined that.
First and foremost, we have to please the old Gothic fans.
Because if they don't like our game,
then this game has no right to exist.
I will say two things.
The first thing is to the fans, is that I hope that they fully understand
the way we embrace the original, the way we respect and try,
we are trying to honor the original, because we understand how important is this game.
Well, the franchise, but Gothic 1 is special for them.
Sometimes I read fans telling, “Okay, I was playing this with my father
and i will play the Remake with my son”
So I hope that they understand that we are doing this
with passion and with all of our heart.
It's the people out there that make us do what we love doing.
It's they enable us to do that and
they are kind of the other half of that,
that world that kind of only works if the both halves come together.
We being passionate game developers
that pour our hearts and souls
into making the game and the audience
that enjoys playing those games
and kind of keeping it to life over so many years.
And for the future, I would like to play a Remake
in 20 years with Arán, with my son.
He is 2 years old now, but maybe in
15 years or 16 years we can play together.
And he says, “Okay Papa, you did this?” and I say "Yes".
But yeah, but maybe in ten years we can we can play together.
The Nameless Hero - the Nameless Hero
23 meat bugs were harmed during the creation of this video
2 meat bug stews were consumed during the making of this episode
The Sleeper is still sleeping
Everything will be fine.
Wishlist now